本字幕由诸神字幕组出品  仅供学习交流  禁止用于商业用途
From this building, you can look
out over the entire school.
このビルから学校全体が見渡せる
更多中日双语字幕  尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
Yeah. So...
その　そこのAS…
About that AS...
日听&日校：小伍 gen   翻译&校对：mam 小江   时间轴：Foyzi   压制：結城結衣
電波妨害はどれくらい持つの
For how long can it jam signals?
120秒程度だ
About 120 seconds. However,
it won't be able to move during that time.
ただし　機体は動くこともできない
でも　学校全体はカバーできる
It can cover the entire school, though.
爆弾の起動を妨害するのか
You're thinking of jamming the bombs?
the
important
part
lol
self-study
Yeah.
その間にみんなを避難させて
What do you think about evacuating everyone
and saving Kyoko within that time?
恭子を助けるのはどうかな
敵の周波数はどうやって見つける
How can we figure out
the enemy's frequency?
あたしがアルゴリズムを書く
I'll write up an algorithm.
In the Arbalest's programming?
You can do that?
アーバレストのプログラムを？できるのか
言語はBAdaでしょ
It's written in BAda, right?
I can do it.
できるわ
How long will it take?
どれくらいかかる
1時間
One hour.
時間を稼ごう
I'll buy you some time.
逆探を開始します
On My Own
Episode 4
Starting the trace.
決心はついたか
Have you decided?
I can't agree to your terms.
そちらの条件はのめない
Oh?
お友達が死んでもいいのか
You don't mind if your friends die?
あの学校の人間が何人死のうと　俺には関係ない
The death of those people in that
school are of no concern to me.
では何人か死なせてみるか
You wouldn't mind if we kill a few, then?
Do what you will.
好きにしろ
もし必要があれば　俺は彼女を殺害するよう命じられている
I have orders to execute her,
should it be deemed necessary.
そちらの要求は？
What are your demands?
That I won't be harmed.
俺の身の安全だ
わかってないな　爆弾を一つ起動してみようか
I don't think you get it.
Want me to set off a bomb to make it clear?
Our negotiations have broken down, then.
では交渉決裂だな
ちょっと
Hey!
Don't worry.
心配するな
But!
でも…
こちらはその娘を確保できればそれでいい
All that matters to me is that
I get the girl in one piece.
だろうな
I figured so.
That AS is a problem, however.
ただし　ASは脅威だ
First, I'll need a guarantee
on it's neutralization.
まずASを無力化する保証が必要だな
では　1100時　泉川二丁目の廃工場にアーバレストを移動させる
Then, at 1100 hours,
I'll have the Arbalest move to the
abandoned factory in Sengawa's 2nd district.
オープンハッチで待機しよう
It will stand by with its hatch open.
監視するぞ
We'll be watching.
Of course you will.
当然だ
千鳥かなめは泉川駅に一人で向かわせる
I'll send Chidori Kaname
unsupervised to Sengawa Station.
Once she's been apprehended,
I'll see to my escape.
引き渡しが済んだら　俺はそのまま消える
いいだろう
Sounds good.
ただし　少しでも段取りがくるったら　爆弾をすべて起動させるぞ
However, should things not go as planned,
I'll blow all those kids to kingdom come.
何度も言っている通り　それは脅しにはならない
As I already told you,
they are no concern of mine.
アル　ECSを解除しろ
Al, cancel ECS.
ラジャー
Roger.
Wait!
待って　どういうこと
What's the big idea!?
Let's move. It's no longer safe here.
移動する　ここは危険だ
No, not that!
そうじゃなくて
どうしてそんなできもしない約束を
Why offer such an impossible arrangement?
Because I made it up, of course.
もちろんでまかせだ
だが　時間が稼げた
But it has bought us time.
ぬけぬけと
He's got some nerve.
先輩　頼みがあります
Senpai, I have a favor to ask.
できたわ
I'm done!
では　始めるとしよう
Let's get started, then.
待って　あたしは？
Wait, what about me?
君は隠れていろ
You stay hidden.
I'll come get you afterwards.
後で迎えに来る
でも　あたしにもまだ何か
But there must still be something I can do.
You've done plenty.
もう十分だ
俺が戻ってこなかったら　これを読め
If I don't return,
read these instructions.
潜伏先と連絡手段が書いてある
It contains whereabouts of a hideout,
and how to contact it.
戻ってこなかったらって…
What do you mean, "if you don't return?"
わかるはずだ
You know exactly what I mean.
Sousuke...
宗介
I'll be back.
いってくる
幸運を
Good luck...
アル　モード4で警戒待機しろ
Al, remain on alert in mode 4.
ラジャー
Roger.
軍曹殿
Sergeant.
What?
なんだ
このまま私を置き去りにしないでください
I humbly request that you reconsider leaving me behind.
なぜそんなことを
Why would you say that?
予感がするからです
You may call it a premonition.
予感？
Premonition?
あなたとお別れする予感です
That you and I are going to part ways.
命令通り待機していろ
Remain on alert, just as I ordered.
あと30分です　指定の場所に人員を
Thirty minutes to go. Shall we send
men to the designated location?
必要ない　どうせはったりだ
There's no need.
He was just bluffing.
では…
Then...
何かあったら　容赦なくドカンだ
If anything goes awry,
we'll answer back in an explosive fashion.
出しゃばっちゃダメ
Don't butt in.
ちゃんとこの場で　大人しく…
Just stay here and keep quiet.
なに　これ
What... was that?
This is the student council.
こちらは生徒会です
つい先ほど　北校舎4階で重大な災害が発生しました
A short moment ago,
a serious disaster occurred on
the fourth floor of the north building.
Study hall
ご想像の通り　相良くんです
As I'm sure you've guessed, it's Sagara-kun.
Study hall
不幸な事故により　彼の毒ガスが漏洩しました
Due to an unfortunate accident,
his poison gas has leaked.
今すぐ校外に避難してください
Please evacuate the building immediately.
毒ガス？
Poison gas?
バカな
No way...
終わりだ
Game over.
爆発しない
They're not exploding!
どうなってる
What the hell happened!?
非常に強力な電波妨害です
Detecting powerful electronic jamming on-site!
すぐに発信元を
Pinpointing the source!
逃げろ
Run!
Sagara's gone and done it again!
相良の奴　またやりやがった
死ぬぞ
We're gonna die!
さすがに速い
As expeditious as I predicted.
電波妨害は継続中
We're still being jammed!
It's coming from...
発信元は…
あれは…
That's...
いつの間に
When did it...
全ユニット　ポイントデルタのASを攻撃しろ　大至急だ
All units, attack the AS
at Point Delta! Immediately!
こちらのコダールは？
What about our Codarls?
呼び戻せ
Call them back!
3機ともだ
All three of them!
警告　敵歩兵12名を捕捉
Warning: enemy infantry detected,
count twelve. Range, one.
距離1　攻撃を受けています
Currently under fire.
ジャミング時間は？
What's the jamming time?
残り90秒です
Ninety seconds remaining.
常盤
Tokiwa!
相良くん
Sagara-kun!
助けに来た
I've come to save you.
し…知らない人たちが…
Th-These strangers, they...
カナちゃんは？
What about Kana-chan?
無事なの？
Is she safe!?
無事だ　安全な場所に
Rest assured, she is safe.
Wh-What?
なに
気にするな
Don't worry about it.
But...
そんな…
起爆装置をバイパスする
I'll bypass the detonator.
動くなよ
Don't move.
ジャミング終了まで　あと20秒
Jamming duration, twenty seconds remaining.
Only one of four cables is the correct one...
4本のケーブルのうち　正解は一つだけ
どれだ
Which is it?
Ten seconds remaining.
あと10秒
Eight.
8 7 6
Seven.
Six.
ジャミング停止　退避します
Jamming ceased. Abandoning position.
相良くん
Sagara-kun...
まだ動くな
Don't move yet.
ねぇ　説明して
Hey, explain this to me.
私　何も知らずに死にたくない
I don't wanna die while being left in the dark.
Who exactly are you?
あなたは一体何者なの
He's a hired killer.
殺し屋だ
ようやく会えたな　相良宗介
So, we meet at last, Sagara Sousuke.
お嬢さん　そいつが高校生だなんてのは嘘っぱちだ
Young lady, don't be fooled by this
fraud of a high school student.
Stop it!
やめろ
文書を偽造して　この学校に潜入したのさ
His paperwork was forged so
he could worm himself into this school,
千鳥かなめのために
all for the sake of Chidori Kaname.
カナちゃんの？
For Kana-chan?
俺は…
I'm...
常盤さん　どこにいるの
Tokiwa-san!
Where are you!?
返事して
Answer me!
みんな避難しちゃったわよ
Everyone's been evacuated!
Hurry and get over here!
早く出てきて
教師のようです
Must be a teacher.
Wh-What's going on here!?
な…何なんです　ここは関係者以外…
You're not authorized to be—
千鳥かなめの居場所はどこだ
Where is Chidori Kaname located?
だ…大丈夫よ　常盤さん
D-Don't worry, Tokiwa-san.
I won't let these people hurt you!
私がこの人たちを説得してみせますから
誰？
Who... are you?
What?
なに
目を閉じていろ　常盤
Keep your eyes shut, Tokiwa!
Damn!
くそ
レイス　女だったとはな
Wraith.
So, you're a woman?
今まで何をしていた
Where have you been all this time?
こちらのセリフだ
I could ask you the same thing.
お前らを探していた
I've been looking all over for you both.
敵AS3機接近　迎撃の準備を
Enemy AS's approaching, count three.
Preparing to intercept.
来い
Come here.
ラジャー
Roger.
どうするつもりだ
What do you intend to do?
戦う
Fight.
Tokiwa!
常盤
楽しい毎日だった
Those were fun times we had.
ありがとう
Thank you.
照準波検知　2　1
Targeting waves detected.
Two.
One.
くそ
Crap!
軍曹　相良軍曹
Sergeant! Sergeant Sagara!
私が手当てをする　お前は急げ
I'll look after her!
You hurry and go!
軍曹　何やってる
Sergeant, what are you doing!?
敵が来るぞ
The enemy's coming!
何の用だ
What do you want?
苦戦しているようだね
Looks like you're experiencing difficulties.
おかげさまでな　女も見つからんし
How nice of you to notice.
The girl still hasn't been found, either.
もうお手上げだ
This mission is a failure.
そうでもないさ
I wouldn't say that.
相良宗介を人質に取ればいい
All we have to do is take
Sagara Sousuke hostage.
Oh?
無茶なことを
That's insane.
奴は今もこうやって暴れまくっている
He's still in the middle of his rampage!
もう少し釘付けにしておいてほしい
All I need is for you to keep him
immobile for a moment.
I'll be there soon.
すぐに行くから
あなたが行く必要があるのですか
Is it necessary for you to go?
たまにはね　運動もしておかないと
Every now and then.
A genius needs his exercise.
どうか　お怪我のないように
Please, try not to get hurt.
ありがとう　サビーナ
Thank you, Sabina.
すぐに戻るよ
I won't be gone long.
これで　3機
That makes... three.
所属不明の輸送機を探知
Transport plane detected.
Affiliation, unknown.
何かが　降下した
Did it... drop something!?
6時　距離0
Six o'clock, range zero.
エリゴールタイプを上回る出力　運動性
Output and mobility surpasses
that of the Eligor type.
非常に危険です
Situation is extremely dangerous.
I recommend immediate withdrawal.
即時撤退を推奨します
さて　相良くん
Well then, Sagara-kun.
It's him!
奴か
最後の警告だよ
This is your final warning.
諦めて彼女を渡す気はないかな
Won't you give up this useless struggle
and hand the girl over?
答えならわかっているだろう
I think you already know
the answer to that!
まあ　そうだろうね
Yes, I suppose I do.
でも　そういう物分かりの悪さ
But that lack of understanding you display...
もしかして　カッコいいとでも思ってるの
Did you think that made you
seem cool or something?
何の話だ
What're you talking about?
ちょっとね　そういうの…
Well, you know. It's just that...
嫌いなんだよ
I hate that kind of thing!
恭…子
Kyoko...
なぜここにいる
What are you doing here!?
Kyoko!
恭子
やだ　恭子
It can't be, Kyoko!
Stay back!
I'm giving her first aid!
下がってろ　救急処置する
助かるの？
Will she make it!?
まだわからない
I don't know yet.
ごめん…なさい
I'm... sorry...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい…
I'm sor—
見えているんだろう
You can see it, can't you?
やめて
Stop it!
You get it, don't you?
もうわかっているだろう
殺さないで
Don't kill him!
僕は苛立っている
You've caught me in a bad mood.
お願いだから
I'm begging you!
君にしか止められないよ
The only one who can stop this is you.
愛してもいいから
It's okay to love me!
その健気さと　強さを
This heroism,
this strength...
努力するから
I swear, I'll try my best!
なぜ　この男に
Why are they for him!?
Generator, stopped.
ジェネレータ　停止
コンデンサ　全て破損
All condensers, damaged.
I recommend you abandon mech... and esc—
機体を放棄し　脱出を…
ご苦労だった
You performed splendidly,
アル
Al...
除隊を…許可する
Your discharge...
is approved!
もうやめて
Stop it!
千鳥
Chidori!
ついていくから
I'll go, all right!?
誰にかな
With whom, pray tell?
あなたに
With you...
あなたについていくから
I'll go with you!
Chidori, stop!
千鳥　やめろ
千鳥
Chidori!
聞こえたよね　相良くん
You heard her, Sagara-kun!
千鳥　やめろ
Chidori... Stop!
千鳥
Chidori!
もういいの
Enough already!
さようなら
Goodbye...
絶対に…
I swear...
絶対に…連れ戻す
I swear I'll bring you back!
絶対に
No matter the method!
No matter the cost!
この場に絶対に連れ戻す
I'll bring you back to this place,
no matter what!
千鳥ー
Chidori!
行け　大佐殿をお守りしろ
Go! Protect the captain!
カリーニンさん
Mr. Kalinin!
You mustn't, ma'am! Hurry!
駄目です　急いで
ヤンさん
Mr. Yang!
大佐…逃げて
Captain... Run!
ヤンさん
Mr. Yang!
こちらアルファ6　敵の指揮官を確保した
This is Alpha 6.
The enemy commander has been captured!
立て
Stand up!
どけ
Move it!
Stop!
やめ…
ったく　あちこち湧いてきやがるわね
Man!
These creeps are crawling all over this place.
メリッサ
Melissa!
戦況は？
What's our situation?
この基地は落ちます
This base is lost.
ダナンに退避を命じましたけど　どれだけたどり着いたか
I've ordered a withdrawal to the Danaan,
but I'm not sure how many made it there...
カリーニンさんも後に残りました
Mr. Kalinin remained behind, too.
I see...
そう
クルーゾーさんとウェーバーさんも音信不通です
I haven't heard from
Mr. Clouseau or Mr. Weber.
恐らく…もう…
Perhaps they're already...
ちくしょうっ　このツケは必ず払わせてやるわ
Damn it, I swear
I'll make them pay for this!
I intend to as well.
私もそのつもりです
そうこないとね
That's what I like to hear.
愛してるわよ　テッサ
I love you, Tessa.
私もです
And I, you!
お待ちしておりました　艦長
We've been awaiting your arrival, Captain.
七つの海を支配する人類史上最強の艦
The mightiest ship in human history, ruler of the seven seas:
The Tuatha de Danaan, is ready to depart at a moment's notice.
トゥアハー・デ・ダナンはいつでも出航可能です
どうぞ　ご命令を
By your command!
Mr. Mardukas...
マデューカスさん
まったく　呆れました
I swear, you've found me speechless.
こんな時にまだ規律？
You still adhere to discipline
at a time like this?
It's at times like these that
discipline is needed the most.
こんな時にこそ　規律が最も大切です
総員　乗艦
All hands, board ship!
最終点検を実行
Performing final inspection.
A群完了　B群完了
Group A, complete. Group B, complete.
Group C, conditionally complete.
C群　条件付きで完了
XOの承認を
Awaiting acknowledgement from XO.
確認しました　艦長
I have confirmed, Captain.
結構
Very well.
前進　3分の1
Ahead, one third!
アイ　マム
Aye, ma'am. Ahead, one third!
前進　3分の1
Ahead, one third.
魚雷発射管　全て開放
Open all torpedo tubes!
アイ　マム
Aye, ma'am.
Open all torpedo tubes!
全ての魚雷発射管を開放
Opening all torpedo tubes!
コンタクト
Contact!
どでかいのがいますぜ　真正面
There's a huge one, dead ahead!
上等よ
That's just fine.
全弾発射と同時に　最大戦速
Launch all torpedoes as we go
to full combat speed!
アイアイ　マム
Aye aye, ma'am.
全弾発射と同時に　最大戦速
Simultaneously launch all torpedoes,
while reaching combat speed!
総員　衝撃に備えて
All hands, brace for impact!
怯まないで
Don't falter!
Keep pushing ahead!
前進そのまま
今の射撃は…
Who fired those shots!?
来ると思ったぜ
We figured you'd come!
ぎりぎりで間に合ったな
Seems like we made it just in time.
ウェーバーさん　クルーゾーさん
Mr. Weber!
Mr. Clouseau!
まったく　しぶとい奴らです
Those boys really are tenacious ones.
それがうちの強みです
That's what makes us so capable.
第13ハッチを開放して
Open hatch 13.
2機の回収後　敵の包囲網を突破します
After recovering the two mechs,
we'll break through the enemy's net.
潜航準備
Prepare to dive!
Aye aye, ma'am! Prepare to dive!
アイアイ　マム
潜航準備
みんな　大変な状況だけど　気持ちを強く持ってね
I know this is a terrible situation,
but I need all of you to be strong.
学校施設の復旧までは　まだ当分かかりそうです
It seems it's going to be a while before repairs to our facilities are finished.
Things aren't going to be
the same for a while,
その間　閉塞的な体制にはなるけれど
but I'm going to try my best,
and so I hope all of you wil—
先生も頑張るから　みんなもめ…
相良くん
Sagara-kun!
もういろいろと言われていると思う
I imagine you've already been
told a number of things.
あの白いASに乗っていたのは俺だ
I'm the one who was inside that white AS.
どうすれば届くのだろう
俺はある傭兵部隊のエージェントで　現役の操縦兵だった
I was an agent for a mercenary force...
and an AS operator on active duty.
黙っていて　すまなかった
I'm sorry... that I hid this from you!
強い風に声も途切れ
すまなかっただって？
You're sorry!?
何のために戦うの
それ　常磐に聞かせてやれよ
You should tell that to Tokiwa!
あいつ　今も入院してんだぞ
She's still in the hospital!
Ono-D, please stop!
小野D　やめてよ
傷だらけの愛
It's cruel, what you put her through!
常磐がかわいそうじゃねぇか
死んでるみたいに生きている
お前　何も感じねぇのかよ
Don't you feel any remorse at all!?
世界よ　あなたを殺したのは誰
Enough with the silent treatment!
Weren't we friends!?
ふざけんなよ　友達じゃなかったのかよ
Say something!
何とか言えよ
Can I see you　この命の最期に
Say something...
綺麗な朝日を見ていたい　あなたに抱かれて
何とか言えって
Say anything!
お前…お前　何しに来たんだよ
What...
What did you even come here for!?
Can I be true　どの道を選んでみても
言っておきたかっただけだ
I came here to request a favor.
What?
なに…
あなたの面影　探してしまう　何時だって
必ず千鳥を連れて帰る
I'll be sure to bring Chidori back.
必ずここに連れて帰る
I swear to you, I'll bring her back here!
せめて　届いて　私のyes
何があっても　どんなことがあっても
No matter the cost.
No matter what awaits me.
So, when that time comes,
welcome her back with open arms.
だからその時は　彼女を迎えてやってくれ
That's all that I wanted to say.
俺が言いたいのは　それだけだ
Episode 5
Next time: "Welcome to the Jungle."
次回 WELCOME TO THE JUNGLE